Bertram D. Lewin Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings File, 1908-1971 (Box 13-20)
  - By Lewin (Box 13)
    - Manuscripts and related materials
      - The Psychoanalysis of Elation, 1950-1952
      - Psychoanalytic Education, circa 1964
      - Psychological Analysis of Hitler: His Life and Legend, with Walter C. Langer, 1944
        Available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 19,236.1
      - Psychoanalytic etymology
        - Bunker, Henry, 1926
        - Miscellaneous matter, circa 1925, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - "Psychosomatic Medicine: Synthesis or Integration," a spoof lecture, University of Pittsburgh Medical School, Pittsburgh, Pa., circa 1945
        - Drafts
        - Slides
      - "Reflections on Affect," 1964
      - "Remarks on Creativity, Imagery, and the Dream," 1969
      - Remarks on the atomic bomb, 29 Nov. 1945
      - Reviews, miscellaneous, 1930-1959
      - "Science and the Homunculus," 1968-1970
      - "Der Sensitive Beziehungswahn," presentation by Lewin, undated
      - "Sleep, Narcissistic Neurosis, and the Analytic Situation," 1954
      - "Sleep, the Mouth, and the Dream Screen," English and Spanish translations, 1946
      - Speeches, 1970
      - "Teachings and the Beginning of Theory," 1965
      - "The Train Ride," 1969-1970
      - "When Adults Tease," 1930 (Box 18)
      - Wolf-Man materials, 1926-1959
      - Miscellaneous research matter
        - Bibliographies, 1955-1970
        - Drafts and related material, 1942-1964, undated
        - Notebooks, 1935, 1941-1947
        - Notes
          - Affects and free association, undated
          - Alphabetically arranged data, 1961-1968, (2 folders)
          - Miscellaneous, 1920-1965
          - Visual image, 1952-1968, undated
          - Quotations, undated (Box 19)
    - Printed matter
      - Articles, 1926-1971, (3 folders)
      - Book reviews, 1940-1947, undated
      - Spanish translations, 1945-1968
  - By others
    - Manuscripts and related materials
      - Benjamin, John D., circa 1965
      - Greenacre, Phyllis, introduction of Lewin at the Freud Lecture, New York Psychoanalytic Institute and Society, New York, N.Y., 27 May 1957
      - Janet, Pierre, "Les Obsessions et La Psychasthenie," 1908
      - Langer, Walter C., Psychological Analysis of Hitler: His Life and Legend, 1944 See Container 16, Psychological Analysis of Hitler
      - Poetry
        - Isakower, Otto, 1954-1959
        - Miscellaneous, 1953-1956, undated (Box 20)
      - Ross, Helen, lectures
        - Child development, 1965-1966
        - Theoretical and clinical study, 1966
    - Miscellaneous printed matter
      - Bonaparte, Princess Marie, notebooks (facsimile), undated
      - Other, 1940-1969, undated, (2 folders)
- Oversize, 1913-circa 1970 (Box OV 1)
  Oversize material consisting of a diploma, certificate, and photographs.
  Arranged and described according to the series, folders, and containers from which the items were removed.
  - Family and School Papers (Box OV 1)
    - Student papers
      - San Antonio High School, San Antonio, Tex.
        - Graduation program and diploma, 1913 (Container 2)
  - Subject File
    - Certification papers and miscellaneous documents, 1927-1957 (Container 7)
    - Photographs and lantern slides, circa 1920-circa 1970 (Container 9)